window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Computer_Network — Slot 10 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Network — Slot 10",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>A link has a transmission speed of \\(10^{6}\\) bits/sec. It uses data packets of size 1000 bytes each. Assume that the acknowledgment has negligible transmission delay, and that its propagation delay is the same as the data propagation delay. Also assume that the processing delays at nodes are negligible. The efficiency of the stop-and-wait protocol in this setup is exactly 25%. The value of the one-way propagation delay (in milliseconds) is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "12",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8056/gate2015-2-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Consider a LAN with four nodes \\(S_{1},S_{2},S_{3} \\; and \\; S_{4}\\) . Time is divided into fixed-size slots, and a node can begin its transmission only at the beginning of a slot. A collision is said to have occurred if more than one node transmit in the same slot. The probabilities of generation of a frame in a time slot by \\(S_{1},S_{2},S_{3} \\; and \\;  S_{4}\\) are 0.1, 0.2, 0.3 and 0.4, respectively. The probability of sending a frame in the first slot without any collision by any of these four stations is _____________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "0.4",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8253/gate2015-1-29#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that the stop-and-wait protocol is used on a link with a bit rate of 64 kilobits per second and 20 milliseconds propagation delay. Assume that the transmission time for the acknowledgement and the processing time at nodes are negligible. Then the minimum frame size in bytes to achieve a link utilization of at least 50% is______________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "320",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8363/gate2015-1-26#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>In one of the pairs of protocols given below, both the protocols can use multiple TCP connections between the same client and the server. Which one is that? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>HTTP, FTP</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>HTTP, TELNET</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>FTP, SMTP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>HTTP, SMTP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>HTTP, FTP</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8214/gate2015-1-17#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following fields of an IP header is NOT modified by a typical IP router? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Checksum</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Source address</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Time to Live (TTL)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Length</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Source address</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8220/gate2015-1-16#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that everyone in a group of N people wants to communicate secretly with the N-1 others using symmetric key cryptographic system. The communication between any two persons should not be decodable by the others in the group. The number of keys required in the system as a whole to satisfy the confidentiality requirement is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2N</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>N(N-1)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>N(N-1)/2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((N-1)^{2}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>N(N-1)/2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8244/gate2015-1-14#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Suppose two hosts use a TCP connection to transfer a large file. Which of the following statements is/are FALSE with respect to the TCP connection?<br>\nI. If the sequence number of a segment is m, then the sequence number of the subsequent segment is always m+1.<br>\nII. If the estimated round trip time at any given point of time is t sec, the value of the retransmission timeout is always set to greater than or equal to t sec. <br>\nIII. The size of the advertised window never changes during the course of the TCP connection.<br>\nIV. The number of unacknowledged bytes at the sender is always less than or equal to the advertised window. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>III only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I and III only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I and IV only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II and IV only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>I and III only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8217/gate2015-1-13#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>An organization is granted the block 130.34.12.64/26. It needs to have 4 subnets. Which of the following is not an address of this organization? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>130.34.12.124</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>130.34.12.89</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>130.34.12.70</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>130.34.12.132</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>130.34.12.132</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/17446/isro2014-75\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is not a valid multicast MAC address? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>01:00:5E:00:00:00</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>01:00:5E:00:00:FF</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>01:00:5E:00:FF:FF</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>01:00:5E:FF:FF:FF</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>01:00:5E:FF:FF:FF</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/17449/isro2014-71\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>A mechanism or technology used in Ethernet by which two connected devices choose common transmission parameters such as speed, duplex mode and flow control is called <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Autosense</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Synchronization</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Pinging</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Auto negotiation</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Auto negotiation</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55011/isro2014-61\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Suppose you are browsing the world wide web using a web browser and trying to access the web servers. What is the underlying protocol and port number that are being used? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>UDP, 80</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>TCP, 80</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>TCP, 25</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>UDP, 25</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>TCP, 80</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55009/isro2014-60\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Assume the following information.<br>Original timestamp value = 46<br>Receive  timestamp value = 59<br>Transmit timestamp value = 60<br>Timestamp at arrival of packet = 69<br>Which of the following statements is correct? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Receive clock should go back by 3 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Transmit and Receive clocks are synchronized</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Transmit clock should go back by 3 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Receive clock should go ahead by 1 milliseconds</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Receive clock should go back by 3 milliseconds</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/17439/isro2014-58\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>A supernet has a first address of 205.16.32.0 and a supernet mask of 255.255.248.0. A router receives 4 packets with the following destination addresses.which packet belongs to this supernet? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>205.16.42.56</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>205.17.32.76</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>205.16.31.10</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>205.16.39.44</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>205.16.39.44</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/17443/isro2014-57\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>An IP packet has arrived with the first 8 bits as 0100 0010. Which of the following is correct? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The number of hops this packet can travel is 2.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The total number of bytes in header is 16 bytes</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The upper layer protocol is ICMP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The receiver rejects the packet</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>The receiver rejects the packet</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/54125/isro2014-55\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Consider a 50 kbps satellite channel with a 500 milliseconds round trip propagation delay. If the sender wants to transmit 1000 bit frames, how much time will it take for the receiver to receive the frame? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>250 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>20 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>520 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>270 milliseconds</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>270 milliseconds</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/54975/isro2014-45\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
